He had the life expectancy of a match.
The Key is a drama, romance, war film directed by Carol Reed.
In wartime England, circa 1941, poorly-armed tugs are sent into
"U-Boat Alley" to rescue damaged Allied ships.
An American named David Ross arrives to captain one of these tugs.
He's given a key by a fellow tugboat-man -- a key to an
apartment and its pretty female resident.
Should something happen to the friend, Ross can use the key.
Capt. David Ross, played by William Holden.
Stella, played by Sophia Loren.
Capt. Chris Ford, played by Trevor Howard.
Cmdr. Wadlow, played by Bernard Lee.
Van Dam, played by Oskar Homolka.
Kane, played by Kieron Moore.
The Key is a 1958 British-American war film set in
1941 during the Battle of the Atlantic.
It was based on the 1951 novel Stella by Jan de Hartog (later republished as
The Distant Shore and The Key) and was directed by Carol Reed.
William Holden, Sophia Loren and Trevor Howard starred in the production.
The key to a flat in wartime Britain may augur bad luck for a succession of tug captains of the Royal Navy whose task is to rescue crippled ships in "U-boat
Alley." As each takes possession from his unfortunate predecessor, the flat's other occupant, a Swiss expatriate named Stella, apparently comes with it.
The latest captain struggles with his conflicting fears
and affection for its apparent jinx.
The tone is emotional.